// creating an array and passing the number,questions and answers

let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "Which of the following is an universal gate ?",
        answer: "NAND gate",
        options: [
            "NAND gate",
            "OR gate",
            "AND gate",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "A device which converts BCD to seven segments is called?",
        answer: "Decoder",
        options: [
            "Encoder",
            "Decoder",
            "Multiplexer",
            "Demultiplexer"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "The basic storage element in a digital system is …",
        answer: "Flip-Flop",
        options: [
            "Flip-Flop",
            "Counter",
            "Multiplexer",
            "Encoder"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "Which device has one input and many outputs?",
        answer: "Demultiplexer",
        options: [
            "Multiplexer",
            "Counter",
            "Demultiplexer",
            "Flip-Flop"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "The register is a type of ...",
        answer: "Sequential circuit",
        options: [
            "Sequential circuit",
            "Combinational circuit",
            "CPU",
            "Latches"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "A register that is used to store binary information is called ?",
        answer: "Binary register",
        options: [
            "Data register",
            "Binary register",
            "Shift register",
            "D – Register"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "Registers capable of shifting in one direction is ...",
        answer: "Unidirectional shift register",
        options: [
            "Universal shift register",
            "Unidirectional shift register",
            "Unipolar shift register",
            "Unique shift register"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "Size of int in Java ?",
        answer: "32 bit",
        options: [
            "16 bit",
            "32 bit",
            "64 bit",
            "Depends on execution environment"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Which is a reserved word in the Java programming language?",
        answer: "Native",
        options: [
            "Method",
            "Native",
            "Array",
            "Subclasses"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Which will legally declare, construct, and initialize an array?",
        answer: `int myList [] = {4, 3, 7};`,
        options: [
        `int [] myList = {"1", "2", "3"};`,
        `int [] myList = (5, 8, 2);`,
        `int myList [] [] = {4,9,7,0};`,
        `int myList [] = {4, 3, 7};`
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "Which statement is true regarding an object?",
        answer: "An object is an instance of a class.",
        options: [
            "An object is what classes instantiated are from.",
            "An object is an instance of a class.",
            "An object is a variable.",
            "An object is a reference to an attribute."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "A package is a collection of ...",
        answer: "Classes and interfaces",
        options: [
            "Classes",
            "Interfaces",
            "Editing tools and interfaces",
            "Classes and interfaces"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "Which of these can be returned by the operator && ?",
        answer: "Integer or Boolean",
        options: [
            "Integer",
            "Boolean",
            "Character",
            "Integer or Boolean"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Which of these can not be used for a variable name in Java?",
        answer: "keyword",
        options: [
            "identifier",
            "keyword",
            "identifier & keyword",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "Perform binary subtraction: 101111 – 010101 = ?",
        answer: "011010",
        options: [
            "100100",
            "010101",
            "011010",
            "011001"
        ]
    }
    
];